The Guernsey Literary & Potato Peel Pie Society is a romance,
drama, history film directed by Mike Newell.
Free-spirited writer Juliet Ashton forms a life-changing bond with the delightful and eccentric Guernsey Literary and Potato Peel
Pie Society, when she decides to write about the book club they formed during the occupation of Guernsey in WWII.
Juliet Ashton, played by Lily James.
Elizabeth McKenna, played by Jessica Brown Findlay.
Sidney Stark, played by Matthew Goode.
Dawsey Adams, played by Michiel Huisman.
Isola Pribby, played by Katherine Parkinson.
Mark Reynolds, played by Glen Powell.
The Guernsey Literary and Potato Peel Pie Society  is a 2018 historical romantic drama film directed by Mike Newell and written by
Kevin Hood, Don Roos and Tom Bezucha, based on the 2008 novel of the same name by Mary Ann Shaffer and Annie Barrows.
The film stars Lily James, Michiel Huisman, Glen Powell, Jessica Brown Findlay,
Katherine Parkinson, Matthew Goode, Tom Courtenay and Penelope Wilton.
Set in 1946, the plot follows a London-based writer who exchanges letters with a resident on the
island of Guernsey, which had been under German occupation during World War II.
A co-production between the United Kingdom, United States, and France, the film was distributed and
financed by StudioCanal and produced by Blueprint Pictures and the Mazur/Kaplan Company.
In 2010, development began on a film adaptation based on Shaffer's novel.
In October 2016, James signed on for the lead role, with Newell set to direct.
The film entered pre-production in January 2017, with principal photography
taking place across England from 23 March to 15 May 2017.
It was released in cinemas in the United Kingdom in
April 2018 and in France in June 2018.
The film grossed $15.7 million worldwide and received
generally positive reviews from critics.
It was distributed in other international areas by
Netflix on 10 August 2018 as an original film.
The film explores themes of london, england, based on novel or
book, world war ii, channel islands, book club.
The tone is emotional.